

Mehmet Onur Üstünel

iOS Developer

About Me

I was born in Tekirdag (Turkey) in 1994. I started studying Mathematics at Aksaray University in 2011. I also studied Computer Science in Poland after has been successful on the Erasmus exam. All of the lessons I took were about software development in Poland. I passed all these lessons with good grades and decided to focus on software development from this period. I also like to convert my hobbies to mastery. Therefore after graduating with my bachelor's degree, I studied at Anadolu University Photography and Videography Department. I also worked for a year as a high school Mathematics Teacher between 2015-2016 years. In 2017, I launched a website for tourists to find photographers while traveling in Turkey. I have made reservations via this website for more than 60 tourists coming to Turkey from different countries of the world. After I decided to improve myself on programming again, I focused on learning iOS programming and took a lot of courses, and started building my iOS applications. I am currently developing mobile applications with Swift for Apple ecosystem in one of the biggest companies in Turkey.

Contact

Birthday: 01.01.1994

+90 542 256 98 41 Phone:

e-mail: ustunel.onur@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/onurustunel/

github.com/onurustunel GitHub:

EXPERIENCE

Cengiz Holding - iOS Developer / 2020 - Presents

I built a native iOS app with Swift programming language for Cengiz Holding Board of Directors which has more than 50,000 workers in Turkey. This application is built totally by me with an AES encryption system to protect the all personal data of workers and owners of the company

Freelance iOS Developer / 2019 - 2020

I produced Native iOS Applications in line with the needs of my customers as a freelance iOS developer. By using my design knowledge, I tried to produce iOS Apps that work smoothly after I prepared the designs of these applications myself and combine them with my coding knowledge.

VenusWed Digital Marketing Specialist / 2017 - 2018

I have built a website for tourists to find their photographer while traveling in Turkey. This site was visited from 86 different countries and has been done more than 60 bookings.

Keşan Final High School - Mathematics Teacher / 2015 - 2016

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree / 2011 - 2015 Aksaray University (Turkey)

Department of Mathematics (Diploma Grade: 85,30)

Study Abroad (Erasmus) / 2014 Bialystok University of Technology (Poland)

Computer Science

- Pedagogical Formation / 2014 2015 Aksaray University (Turkey)
- Associate Degree / 2015 2017 Anadolu University (Turkey)

Photography and Videography Department (Diploma Grade: 71,53)

SKILLS

- MVC MVVM
- AUTO LAYOUT
- REST API
- JSON WEB SERVICES
- FIREBASE
- SOLID PRENCIPLES
- OOP
- GIT (VCS)
- CARTHAGE COCOAPODS
- CORE DATA REALM
 POWERBI
- AES ENCRYPTION
- JWT TOKEN
- CORE ANIMATION
 CORE LOCATION

 - LOTTIE
 - CHARTS

HOBBIES & INTERESTS















